#### Mark A. Urich

619-277-7569

markurich@gmail.com

markurich.com

## **PERSONAL**

I am a problem solver at heart; I enjoy spending hours fixing things and solving puzzles. After over 8 years of working in an academic research lab, generating mountains of genomic data, I decided to change course and pursue a field that allows me to make better use of my passion. I began a career in research with the goal to continuously expand my knowledge and the collective knowledge of humanity. With the amount of data being produced these days, I feel that I can accomplish that goal better through software engineering.

## RECENT PROJECTS

### Anno-JR: Anno-J on Rails

An app for creating and managing sequencing data browsers with Anno-J.

Source: https://github.com/maalur/anno-jr

### **Schmitz Lab Website**

A personal website, built with Rails, designed and developed for a former colleague's research lab. http://schmitzlab.genetics.uga.edu/

#### **Twitter Clone**

A Twitter clone, built with Ruby on Rails and Boostrap.

https://afternoon-savannah-4285.herokuapp.com/ Source: https://github.com/maalur/sample app

## **SKILLS**

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, jQuery, SQL, HTML, CSS, Sass

### **EDUCATION**

# 2009-2011, AS, Grossmont College, Mathematics

Emphasis in biotechnology; Relevant coursework: linear algebra and differential equations.

# 2005-2010, AS, Cuyamaca College, Biology

Emphasis in biotechnology; Relevant coursework: C++ and Java programming.

### **EMPLOYMENT**

## 2013-present, SEQUENCING CONSULTANT

Offered DNA, RNA, and MethylC-seq library preparation services, training, and consulting.

## 2010-2013, LAB TECHNICIAN, The Salk Institute for Biological Studies, Ecker Lab, La Jolla, CA

Studied the role of DNA methylation through high-throughput DNA sequencing. Lead the lab in designing, developing, and enhancing protocols for high-throughput sequencing. Supplied training and support for students and colleagues. Performed key sequencing experiments for a number of research projects, including:

- 1001 Genomes/Epigenomes:

http://www.1001genomes.org/

- NIH Roadmap Epigenomics Mapping Consortium http://www.roadmapepigenomics.org
- Mouse ENCODE: http://www.mouseencode.org/

## 2009, TUTOR, Grossmont Union High School District, La Mesa, CA

Tutored students in Chemistry and Physics as part of the after school ASPIRE program.

## 2005-2010, LAB ASSISTANT, The Salk Institute for Biological Studies, Ecker Lab, La Jolla, CA

Studied ETHYLENE-INSENSITVE5 and its role as a 5' to 3' exoribonuclease.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

A list of my current publications can be found on my Google Scholar page: http://scholar.google.com/citations?user=ZxwExtQAAAAJ